<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Quant Out of Water</title>
    <link>https://rjtk.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Quant Out of Water</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rjtk.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Group Theory, Symmetry, and a Brain Teaser</title>
      <link>https://rjtk.github.io/posts/group-theory-symmetry-and-a-brain-teaser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rjtk.github.io/posts/group-theory-symmetry-and-a-brain-teaser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I review some elementary discrete math concepts, use them to describe and solve a neat brain-teaser, and generalize the solution into a form of robust breadth first search.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lyapunov Stability, Linear Systems, and Semidefinite Programming</title>
      <link>https://rjtk.github.io/posts/lyapunov-stability-linear-systems-and-semidefinite-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rjtk.github.io/posts/lyapunov-stability-linear-systems-and-semidefinite-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dynamical systems are ubiquitous models occuring in science, engineering, and mathematics.  Not only are they used to model real-world dynamic phenomena like the dynamics of chemical plants, population growth, and physical engineered systems, they can also be applied to model algorithms themselves.  This post focuses on &lt;em&gt;linear&lt;/em&gt; dynamical systems, their analysis by means of semidefinite programming, and connections with control theory through the computation of quadratic functionals of their paths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Equations with Jacobi Iteration</title>
      <link>https://rjtk.github.io/posts/solving-equations-with-jacobi-iteration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rjtk.github.io/posts/solving-equations-with-jacobi-iteration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jacobi iteration is a natural idea for solving certain types of nonlinear equations, and reduces to a famous algorithm for linear systems.  This post discusses the algorithm, its convergence, benefits and drawbacks, along with a discussion of examples and pretty pictures 🖼️.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://rjtk.github.io/posts/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rjtk.github.io/posts/introduction/</guid>
      <description>My name is Ryan and I like math.
The title of this blog, Quant out of Water, is more-or-less the first thing that came to mind. However, as I (as of 2022) work as a quant at an hedge fund, and I wanted to write a blog that was not explicitly about finance, this title reflects that motivation. I produced the fish with money using a stable diffusion model. I hope you enjoy some of my writings.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
